

(+65) 8158-6831 | ☑ yang0478@ntu.edu.sg | 🎓 marsrock.net

Research Interests_

My research focuses on developing transfer learning algorithms to enhance the generalization of deep learning models. I am interested in tackling the problem of lack of high-quality annotated data confronting various tasks. Revolving this goal, I mainly study the following topics:

- · Machine learning: transfer learning, especially domain adaptation, multi-task learning, few-shot learning
- Smart sensing: sensing technology under challenging circumstances (limited annotations or noisy data) such as WiFi sensing under spatial dynamics and visual recognition in dark environment
- Interdisciplinary research: ubiquitous smart sensing based on Internet of Things (IoT), computer-aided structural and earthquake engineering, vision-based identification for animal husbandry, face expression recognition and analysis

Education

Nanyang Technological University

Singapore 2016 - 2020

Ph.D., School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering
Supervisor: IEEE Fellow, IFAC Fellow, Prof. Lihua Xie

Sun Yat-sen University

Guanazhou, China

B.S., DEPARTMENT OF DATA AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

2012 - 2016

Experience ____

Chinese Academy of Science

Beijing, China

COMPUTER VISION ADVISOR

April 2019 - Present

• Mentor students and offer professional suggestions on machine learning.

DJI

Shenzhen, China

VISION ENGINEER INTERN

June 2014 - Sep 2014

• Develop an efficient and robust visual tracking algorithm for robotics.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2020	3rd Place Winner , IEEE CVPR 2020 EmotionNet Challenge	Seatle, USA
2019	Winner, IEEE CVPR 2019 UG2+ Challenge (Zero-shot Detection in Rain)	Long beach, USA
2018	Winner, PEER Hub ImageNet Challenge by Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center	Los Angelos, USA
2018	Winner, ACM ICMI 2018 Emotion Recognition Challenge	Colorado, USA
2017	Winner (1/771), JD Global Data Challenge (Livestock face recognition)	Beijing, China
2017	Winner (1/120), Buildathon of Singapore by Ministry of Education (Singapore)	Singapore
2016	Winner (1/20000), Microsoft Beauty of Programming Challenge by Microsoft Research Asia	Shanghai, China
2015	Intel Prize, HackNTU (IoT Solutions for the developing countries)	Taipei, China
2015	Meritorious Winner, American Mathematical Contest In Modeling	USA

DOMESTIC

2020	4th Place Winner (4/4000), National AI Challenge - Person Re-identification	Shenzhen
2019	Winner (1/617), HUAWEI Cloud Garbage Recognition Challenge	Shanghai
2017	Winner-up (2/782), Microsoft Imagine Cup in China	Shanghai
2016	Winner, China Mobile Internet of Things Hackathons	Guangzhou, China
2015	First Prize, National Mobile Internet Innovation Contest	Beijing, China
2015	First Prize, National Undergraduate IOT Design Contest by Ministry of Education (China)	Wuxi, China
2014	First Prize, Humanoid Robotics Hackathon by ALDEBARAN	Shenzhen, China
2013	Undergraduate First-class Scholarship (5% students), Sun Yat-Sen University	Guangzhou, China

Publications _

Journal	
MobileDA: Towards Mobile Domain Adaptation	IEEE IoTJ
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Shuxin Cao, Zhenghua Chen, Lihua Xie	2020
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Learning Gestures from WiFi: A Siamese Recurrent Convolutional Architecture	IEEE IoTJ
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Lihua Xie	2019
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Device-free Occupancy Sensing Platform using WiFi-enabled IoT Devices for Smart Homes	IEEE IoTJ
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2018
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
CareFi: Sedentary Behavior Monitoring System via Commodity WiFi Infrastructures	IEEE TVT
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2018
IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology (IF=5.34)	
Unsupervised WiFi-enabled IoT Device-User Association for Personalized Locationbased	
Service Service	IEEE IOTJ
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Costas Spanos	2018
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Automatic Adversarial Learning Enabled WiFi Indoor Radio Map Construction and	
Adaptation with Mobile Robot	IEEE IoTJ
Han Zou,, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2020
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Region attention networks for pose and occlusion robust facial expression recognition	IEEE TIP
KAI WANG, XIAOJIANG PENG, JIANFEI YANG, DEBIN MENG, YU QIAO	2020
IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (IF=6.79)	
Advancing Image Understanding in Poor Visibility Environments: A Collective Benchmark	
Study	IEEE TIP
Wenhan Yang,, Jianfei Yang	2020
IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (IF=6.79)	
Transfer learning enhanced AR spatial registration for facility maintenance management	AUTOCON
Keyu Chen, Jianfei Yang*, Jack CP Cheng, Weiwei Chen, Chun Ting Li	2020
Automation in Construction (IF=4.31)	
Towards occupant activity driven smart buildings via WiFi-enabled IoT devices and deep	
learning	ENB
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Costas Spanos	2018
Energy and Buildings 2017 (IF=4.50)	
WiFi Fingerprinting Indoor Localization Using Local Feature-Based Deep LSTM	IEEE Systems
ZHENGHUA CHEN, HAN ZOU, JIANFEI YANG, HAO JIANG, LIHUA XIE	2018
IEEE Systems Journal (IF=4.46)	
Semantic-filtered Soft-Split-Aware video captioning with audio-augmented feature	Elsevier
YUECONG XUE, JIANFEI YANG, KEZHI MAO	2018
Neurocomputing (IF=4.07)	
Non-intrusive Occupancy Sensing in Commercial Buildings	ENB
Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
Energy and Buildings 2017 (IF=4.50)	
Compressive perceptual hashing tracking	Elsevier
Long Chen, Zheng Li, Jianfei Yang	2016
Neurocomputing (IF=4.07)	
Conference	
Mind the Discriminability: Asymmetric Adversarial Domain Adaptation	ECCV 2020
·	

2020

Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Zhaoyang Zeng, Lihua Xie

European Conference on Computer Vision

Suppressing Mislabeled Data via Grouping and Self-Attention	ECCV 2020
XIAOJIANG PENG, KAI WANG, ZHAOYANG ZENG, QING LI, JIANFEI YANG, YU QIAO	2020
European Conference on Computer Vision	2020
Suppressing Uncertainties for Large-Scale Facial Expression Recognition	CVPR 2020
Kai Wang, Xiaojiang Peng, Jianfei Yang, Shijian Lu, Yu Qiao	2020
IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2020	
Bootstrap Model Ensemble and Rank Loss for Engagement Intensity Regression	ICMI 2020
Kai Wang*, Jianfei Yang*, Da Guo, Kaipeng Zhang, Xiaojiang Peng, Yu Qiao	2020
ACM International Conference on Multimodal Interaction 2020	
Kervolutional Neural Network	CVPR 2019
Chen Wang, Jianfei Yang, Junsong Yuan, Lihua Xie	2019
IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2019	
WiFi and Vision Multimodal Learning for Accurate and Robust Device-Free Human Activity	
Recognition	CVPR-19 Workshop
Han Zou, Jianfei Yang, Hari Prasanna Das,, Costas J Spanos	2019
CVPR-19 Multimodal workshop	
Machine Learning empowered Occupancy Sensing for Smart Buildings	ICML-19 Workshop
Han Zou, Hari Prasanna Das, Jianfei Yang,, Costas J Spanos	2019
ICML-19 Climate Change Workshop	
Joint Adversarial Domain Adaptation for Resilient WiFi-Enabled Device-Free Gesture	
Recognition	IEEE ICMLA-19
Han Zou, Jianfei Yang, Yuxun Zhou, Costas Spanos	2019
IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA)	
Deep Recurrent Multi-instance Learning with Spatio-temporal Features for Engagement	10111-0
Intensity Prediction	ICMI-18
Jianfei Yang, Kai Wang, Xiaojiang Peng, Yu Qiao	2018
ACM International Conference on Multimodal Interaction 2018	
Cascade attention networks for group emotion recognition with face, body and image	ICMI 10
cues	ICMI-18
Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng Xiaojiang Peng, Yu Qiao	2018
ACM International Conference on Multimodal Interaction 2018	
Consensus Adversarial Domain Adaptation	AAAI-18
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Costas Spanos	2018
AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2018	
Robust WiFi-enabled device-free gesture recognition via unsupervised adversarial	IEEE ICCCN 10
domain adaptation	IEEE ICCCN-18
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2018
IEEE 27th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks	
Deepsense: Device-free human activity recognition via autoencoder long-term recurrent	IEEE ICC-18
convolutional network	TEEE ICC-10
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2018
IEEE International Conference on Communications 2018	
WiFi-enabled device-free gesture recognition for smart home automation	IEEE ICCA-17
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
IEEE 14th International Conference on Control and Automation (ICCA)	
Poster: WiFi-based device-free human activity recognition via automatic representation	IEEE Mobicom-17
learning	TEEL MODICOTTI-TI
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Weixi Gu, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
23rd Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing	
Fine-grained Adaptive Location-independent Activity Recognition using Commodity WiFi	IEEE WCNC-17
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2017
IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference 2017	
Freecount: Device-free crowd counting with commodity WiFi	IEEE Globecom-17
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Weixi Gu, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017

IEEE Global Communications Conference

WiFi-bas	ed Human Identification via Convex Tensor Shapelet Learning	AAAI-17
Han Zou, Y	JXUN ZHOU, JIANFEI YANG, LIHUA XIE, COSTAS SPANOS	2017
AAAI Confe	erence on Artificial Intelligence 2017	
Multiple	kernel representation learning for WiFi-based human activity recognition	IEEE ICMLA-17
Han Zou, Y	jxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Weixi Gu, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
IEEE Intern	national Conference on Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA)	
Freedete	ector: Device-free occupancy detection with commodity wifi	IEEE SECON-17 Workshop
Han Zou, Y	jxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Weixi Gu, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
IEEE Inter	national Conference on Sensing, Communication and Networking (SECON Workshops)	
Online V	isual Tracking via Correlation Filter with Convolutional Networks	IEEE VCIP-16
JIANFEI YAN	g, Zheng Li, Chang-Dong Wang, Weishi Zheng	2016
IEEE Inter	national Conference on Visual Communications and Image Processing 2016	
Compre	sive Perceptual Hashing Tracking with Online Foreground Learning	IEEE ROBIO-15
JIANFEI YAN	g, Zheng Li, Long Chen, Juan Zha	2015
IEEE Interi	national Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics 2015	
Under	Review	
	Stable and Comprehensive Domain Alignment: Max-margin Domain-Adversarial	
Training		0000
	G, HAN ZOU, YUXUN ZHOU, LIHUA XIE	2020
Cluster-l	evel Discrepancy Minimization for Imbalanced Domain Adaptation	
JIANFEI YAN	g, Jiangang Yang, Han Zou, Shuxin Cao, Shizheng Wang, Lihua Xie	2020
	n-based Domain-confused Adversarial Domain Adaptation for Real-world omain Object Recognition	
JIANFEI YAN	g, Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Lihua Xie	2020
Pater	nts	
PCT INT	ernational Patents	
2020	Device-Free Human Identification and Device-Free Gesture Recognition,	WO2020037313
2019	Unsupervised WiFi-Enabled Device-User Association for Personalized Location-based Service,	WO2019226910A1
CHINES	E PATENTS	
2018	People Engagement Prediction by Facial Expression Recognition,	TBD
2018	Robot-aided WiFi-based Indoor Localization,	TBD
Talks		
2019	Smart Sensing based on IoT and Transfer Learning, Institute of Electronics, Chinese Academy of Scien	ces Beijing, China
2018	Multi-task Learning for Structural Engineering, Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center	UCLA, USA
2018	Vision-based Livestock Surveillance for Husbandry and Insurance, National University of Singapore	Singapore
2018	WiFi-based Human Activity Recognition, IEEE WCNC 2018	Barcelona, Spair
2017	Magic Mirror: An IoT and AI based Intelligent Toy, Microsoft	Shanghai, China
2015	Narrator: A Humanoid Robot Presenter with Markup Language, ALDEBARAN	Shenzhen, China
_0.0		

Services___

• **Journal Reviewer:** IEEE IoT Journal, IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics, IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing, IEEE Wireless Communications Magazine, ACM Transactions on Spatial Algorithm and Systems, International Journal of Distributed Sensor Network, Information Fusion, IEEE Access

Skills_____

- Deep learning framework: Pytorch, Keras, Theano, Caffe
- Programming languages: C++, Python, MATLAB, Jave, Scala, R, Javescript, HTML5, Verilog